<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<sbml xmlns="http://www.sbml.org/sbml/level2/version4" level="2" metaid="_585553" version="4">
  <model id="Guyton1972_HeartRateStrokeVolume" name="Guyton1972_HeartRateStrokeVolume" metaid="metaid_0000002">
    <notes>
      <body xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>This a model from the article:      <br/>
                <strong>Circulation: overall regulation.</strong>
                <br/>
          Guyton AC, Coleman TG, Granger HJ.      <em>Annu Rev Physiol</em>
          1972;34:13-46      <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/4334846">4334846</a>
          ,      <br/>
                <strong>Abstract:</strong>
                <br/>
          This article is an experiment, one undertaken primarily because of the
long-term belief of Dr. Victor Hall, Editor of the Annual Review of Physiology fo
r many years, that physiology is, or at least should be, an analytical subject,
and that a method not utilized to its fullest advantage for organizing
review material is the systems analysis. Furthermore, one of the most likely
areas in physiology for which a systems analysis could be of value would be
in a discussion of circulatory regulation. Therefore, this article was undertaken
directly at the request of the editors of the A ogy to attempt the welding togeth
er of a systemsn annuaally Rsiesv ioewf coifr cPuhlaytsoiorlyregulation
with a review of the current literature in this field.
The systems analysis of circulatory regulation developed for this article
is based on earlier, much less extensive analyses (Guyton and Coleman 1, 2); it i
s illustrated in Figure 1. This analysis is comprised of 354 blocks, each of
which represents one or more mathematical equations describing some
physiological facet of circulatory function. In general, each of the functional
blocks has been the subject of research investigation by one or many investigator
s,
but the analysis is based on cumulative knowledge of the circulation
rather than simply on current literature. Therefore, the analysis presented
here is not a review of the current literature but is a framework to show how
the different regulations operate together in the overall system. Later in this
review we will attempt to show some of the voids still present in our knowledge
of circulatory regulation (which is perhaps the most important value
of performing systems analyses), and we will discuss the current research
that is attempting to fill these voids.
A criticism that has often been made against systems analyses, and very
justly so, is that they are usually designed to explain specific phenomena.
Therefore, they too often are based on such bizarre concepts of function that
they not only fail to give correct predictions (other than the specific ones
for which they are designed) but, indeed, often give exactly reverse
predictions. Therefore, the analysis of Figure 1 was based almost entirely on act
ual
experimental data, and it has been tested in computer simulations to see
whether or not it can predict the animal or human results of many different
types of circulatory stresses induced either experimentally or as the result
of clinical abnormalities. Figures 2 through 5 present simulations of some of
these experiments or clinical conditions. They will be described later in the
article.      </p>
            <p>This model was taken from the      <a href="http://www.cellml.org/models">CellML repository</a>
          and automatically converted to SBML.      <br/>
          The original model was:      <a href="http://www.cellml.org/models/guyton_heart_rate_and_stroke_volume_2008_version01">        <strong>Guyton AC, Coleman TG, Granger HJ. (2008) - version01</strong>
                    </a>
                </p>
            <p>This model originates from BioModels Database: A Database of Annotated Published Models (http://www.ebi.ac.uk/biomodels/). It is copyright (c) 2005-2011 The BioModels.net Team.      <br/>
          To the extent possible under law, all copyright and related or neighbouring rights to this encoded model have been dedicated to the public domain worldwide. Please refer to      <a href="http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/" title="Creative Commons CC0">CC0 Public Domain Dedication</a>
          for more information.      </p>
            <p>In summary, you are entitled to use this encoded model in absolutely any manner you deem suitable, verbatim, or with modification, alone or embedded it in a larger context, redistribute it, commercially or not, in a restricted way or not..      <br/>
                <br/>
          To cite BioModels Database, please use:      <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20587024" target="_blank">Li C, Donizelli M, Rodriguez N, Dharuri H, Endler L, Chelliah V, Li L, He E, Henry A, Stefan MI, Snoep JL, Hucka M, Le Novère N, Laibe C (2010) BioModels Database: An enhanced, curated and annotated resource for published quantitative kinetic models. BMC Syst Biol., 4:92.</a>
                </p>
            </body>
      
    </notes>
    <annotation>
      <rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:bqmodel="http://biomodels.net/model-qualifiers/" xmlns:vCard="http://www.w3.org/2001/vcard-rdf/3.0#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:bqbiol="http://biomodels.net/biology-qualifiers/">
        <rdf:Description rdf:about="#metaid_0000002">
          <bqmodel:is>
            <rdf:Bag>
              <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://identifiers.org/biomodels.db/MODEL0911270006"/>
            </rdf:Bag>
          </bqmodel:is>
          <bqmodel:isDescribedBy>
            <rdf:Bag>
              <rdf:li rdf:resource="http://identifiers.org/pubmed/4334846"/>
            </rdf:Bag>
          </bqmodel:isDescribedBy>
        </rdf:Description>
      </rdf:RDF>
    </annotation>
      <listOfCompartments>
      <compartment id="Compartment" metaid="_426206" units="litre" size="1"/>
    </listOfCompartments>
    <listOfParameters>
      <parameter id="QLO" name="QLO" metaid="_426216" value="4.9943" units="dimensionless"/>
      <parameter id="AUR" name="AUR" metaid="_426218" value="1.3" units="dimensionless"/>
      <parameter id="PRA" name="PRA" metaid="_426219" value="0.00852183" units="dimensionless"/>
      <parameter id="HMD" name="HMD" metaid="_426220" value="1" units="dimensionless"/>
      <parameter id="AUHR" constant="false" name="AUHR" metaid="_426222" units="dimensionless"/>
      <parameter id="PRHR" constant="false" name="PRHR" metaid="_426223" units="dimensionless"/>
      <parameter id="HDHR" constant="false" name="HDHR" metaid="_426224" units="dimensionless"/>
      <parameter id="HR" constant="false" name="HR" metaid="_426226" units="dimensionless"/>
      <parameter id="SVO" constant="false" name="SVO" metaid="_426227" units="dimensionless"/>
      <parameter id="PR1LL" name="PR1LL" metaid="_426228" value="0" units="dimensionless"/>
    </listOfParameters>
    <listOfRules>
      <assignmentRule metaid="_426209" variable="AUHR">
        <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">        
          <apply>
            <times/>
            <cn> 72 </cn>
            <ci> AUR </ci>
          </apply>
        </math>
      </assignmentRule>
      <assignmentRule metaid="_426210" variable="PRHR">
        <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">        
          <apply>
            <times/>
            <apply>
              <power/>
              <ci> PR1LL </ci>
              <cn> 0.5 </cn>
            </apply>
            <cn> 5 </cn>
          </apply>
        </math>
      </assignmentRule>
      <assignmentRule metaid="_426212" variable="HDHR">
        <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">        
          <apply>
            <plus/>
            <apply>
              <times/>
              <apply>
                <minus/>
                <ci> HMD </ci>
                <cn> 1 </cn>
              </apply>
              <cn> 0.5 </cn>
            </apply>
            <cn> 1 </cn>
          </apply>
        </math>
      </assignmentRule>
      <assignmentRule metaid="_426213" variable="HR">
        <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">        
          <apply>
            <times/>
            <apply>
              <plus/>
              <ci> AUHR </ci>
              <ci> PRHR </ci>
            </apply>
            <ci> HDHR </ci>
          </apply>
        </math>
      </assignmentRule>
      <assignmentRule metaid="_426214" variable="SVO">
        <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">        
          <apply>
            <divide/>
            <ci> QLO </ci>
            <ci> HR </ci>
          </apply>
        </math>
      </assignmentRule>
    </listOfRules>
  </model>
</sbml>